doseofcolors.com 2018-06-29

# PRIVACY POLICY - Dose of Colors

**Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement describes the privacy practices of  Dose of Colors for data that we collect:

Through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “Apps”)

through our social media pages that we control from which you are accessing this Privacy Statement (collectively, our “Social Media Pages”)

through HTML-formatted email messages that we send you that link to this Privacy Statement and through your communications with us

Collectively, we refer to the Websites, the Apps and our Social Media Pages, as the “Online Services” and, together with offline channels, the “Services.” By using the Services, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement.

**Collection of Personal Data**

“Personal Data” are data that identify you as an individual or relate to an identifiable individual.

At touchpoints throughout your guest journey, we sometimes collect Personal Data  such as: 

Name

Gender

Postal address

Telephone number

Email address

**How We Collect Personal Data**

 We collect Personal Data in a variety of ways:

Online Services. We collect Personal Data when you purchase goods from our Websites or Apps, communicate with us, or otherwise connect with us or post to social media pages, or sign up for a newsletter or participate in a survey, contest or promotional offer.

Customer Care Centers. We collect Personal Data when you communicate with us by email, fax or via online chat services or contact customer service. These communications may be recorded for purposes of quality assurance and training.

**Collection of Other Data**

“Other Data” are data that generally do not reveal your specific identity or do not directly relate to an individual. To the extent Other Data reveal your specific identity or relate to an individual, we will treat Other Data as Personal Data. Other Data include:

Browser and device data

App usage data

Data collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies

Demographic data and other data provided by you

Aggregated data

**How We Collect Other Data**

We collect Other Data in a variety of ways:

Your browser or device. We collect certain data through your browser or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, internet browser type and version and the name and version of the Online Services (such as the Apps) you are using. We use this data to ensure that the Online Services function properly. 

Your use of the Apps. We collect certain data when you download and use an App, such as App usage data, the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what data and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number. 

**Cookies.**

We collect certain data from cookies, which are pieces of data stored directly on the computer or mobile device that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect data such as browser type, time spent on the Online Services, pages visited, referring URL, language preferences, and other aggregated traffic data. We use the data for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display data more effectively, to collect statistical data, to personalize your experience while using the Online Services and to recognize your computer to assist your use of the Online Services. We also gather statistical data about use of the Online Services to continually improve design and functionality, understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions.

Cookies further allow us to select which advertisements or offers are most likely to appeal to you and display them while you are using the Online Services or to send marketing emails. We also use cookies to track responses to online advertisements and marketing emails

If you do not want data collected with cookies, you can learn more about controlling cookies at http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookes/index.htm. 

You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Online Services. For example, you will not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs. At this time, we do not respond to browser “Do-Not-Track” signals

Pixel Tags and other similar technologies. We collect data from pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs), which are used with some Online Services to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Online Services (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Online Services.

**Analytics.** We collect data through Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics, which use cookies and technologies to collect and analyze data about use of the Services. These services collect data regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt out browser add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout. You can learn more about Adobe and opt out by visiting http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html.

Adobe Flash technology (such as Flash Local Shared Objects (“Flash LSOs”)) and other similar technologies. We collect data through Flash LSOs and other technologies on some Websites to, among other things, collect and store data about your use of the Online Services. If you do not want Flash LSOs stored on your computer, you can adjust the settings of your Flash player to block Flash LSO storage using the tools contained in the Website Storage Settings Panel at http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html. You can also control Flash LSOs by going to the Global Storage Settings Panel at http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html and following the instructions (which include instructions that explain, for example, how to delete existing Flash LSOs (referred to as “information” on the Macromedia site), how to prevent Flash LSOs from being placed on your computer without your being asked, and (for Flash Player 8 and later) how to block Flash LSOs that are not being delivered by the operator of the page you are on at the time). Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications, including those used with the Online Services. For more information, please refer to https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html.

**Your IP Address**. We collect your IP address, a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files when a user accesses the Online Services, along with the time of the visit and the pages that were visited. We use IP addresses to calculate usage levels, diagnose server problems and administer the Online Services. We also may derive your approximate location from your IP address.

Aggregated Data. We may aggregate data that we collected and this aggregated data will not personally identify you or any other user.

**Use of Personal Data and Other Data  **We use Personal Data and Other Data to provide you with services, to develop new offerings and to protect Dose of Colors. In some instances, we will request that you provide Personal Data or Other Data to us directly. If you do not provide the data that we request, or prohibit us from collecting such data, we may not be able to provide the requested Services and or goods you are requesting. 

We use Personal Data and Other Data for our legitimate business interests, including the following:

Provide the Services you request. We use Personal Data and Other Data to provide Services you request, including: 

To support our electronic receipt program. When you provide an email address in identifying your order, we use that email address to send you a copy of your product invoice

We will use Personal Data and Other Data to manage our relationship with you, because we have a legitimate interest to do so and/or to comply with a legal obligation.

**Personalize the Services according to your Personal Preferences**. We use Personal Data and Other Data to personalize the Services and improve your experiences, including when you contact our customer service department, to: 

Customize your experience according to your Personal Preferences

Communicate with you about goods according to your Personal Preferences. We use Personal Data and Other Data to: 

Send you marketing communications and promotional offers, as well as periodic customer satisfaction, market research or quality assurance surveys

Loyalty Programs. We use Personal Data and Other Data to: 

  * Offer and manage your participation in our global loyalty programs
  * Send you offers, promotions and information about your account status and activities
  * Assess your benefits
  * Manage your choices regarding how you wish to earn, track and use your points
  * Sweepstakes, activities, events and promotions. We use Personal Data and Other Data to allow you to participate in sweepstakes, contests and other promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules and may contain additional information about how we use and disclose your Personal Data. We suggest that you read any such rules carefully.
  * We use Personal Data and Other Data in this way with your consent, to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

**Business Purposes**. We use Personal Data and Other Data for data analysis, audits, security and fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new goods and services, enhancing, improving or modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.

We use Personal Data and Other Data in this way to manage our contractual relationship with you, comply with a legal obligation and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

**Disclosure of Personal Data and Other Data**

We may need to share Personal Data with third-party service providers to assist us in operating the Website and/or to conduct some processing of your information on our behalf as described below

In addition, we are not responsible for the data collection, use, disclosure or security policies or practices of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any Personal Data you disclose to other organizations through or the Apps or our Social Media Pages.

**Third Party Advertisers**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding goods and services that may interest you when you access the Dose of Colors website or any future or current app owned and or operated by Dose of Colors.  To serve such advertisements, these companies place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn about your choices in connection with it, please visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp and http://www.aboutads.info/. To opt out of the practice, you may download the AppChoices app at www.aboutads.info/appchoices.

**Security**

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Data. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of your account has been compromised), please immediately notify us in accordance with the “Contacting Us”section, below.

**LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES** :

In order to anticipate your needs, our website provides links to other web sites and third parties for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing or disclosure of data (including personal data) by such third parties. We encourage you to contact these third parties to ask questions about their privacy practices, policies and security measures before disclosing any personal data. We recommend that you review the privacy statements and policies of linked web sites to understand how those web sites collect, use and store information.

**Choices, Access and Retention**

 You have choices when it comes to how we use your data and we want to ensure you have the information to make the choices that are right for you. 

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails, you may opt out by following the instructions in any such email you receive from us or reach out to us by info@doseofcolors.com.

In addition, members of our loyalty programs can opt out from marketing-related emails through their program account, or by sending an email to Customer Service  at [info@doseofcolors.com](mailto:info@doseofcolors.com). We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable

**How You Can Access, Change or Suppress Your Personal Data**

In your request, please make clear what Personal Data you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Data suppressed from our database, or other limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Data. For your protection, we only fulfill requests for the Personal Data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before fulfilling your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. 

Please note that we often need to retain certain data for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such purchase). There may also be residual data that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed. In addition, there may be certain data that we may not allow you to review for legal, security or other reasons.

**Retention**

We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. 

The criteria used to determine our retention periods include: 

The length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you and provide the Services to you (for example, for as long as you have an account with us or keep purchasing our products)

Whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject (for example, certain laws require us to keep records of your transactions for a certain period of time before we can delete them)

Whether retention is advisable considering our legal position (such as, for statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations)

**Sensitive Data**

Unless specifically requested, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, on or through the Services or otherwise to us, any Sensitive Personal Data (e.g., social security numbers, national identification number, data related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, ideological or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background, trade union membership, or administrative or criminal proceedings and sanctions).

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at info@doseofcolors.com
